Johnathan Pruitt

832-540-2812 | pruittj1998@gmail.com

Github: https://github.com/linxerz | Blog: https://medium.com/@pruittj2000 | Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jakirap

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Experienced in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript based programming and a background in building and fixing PC and phones. Possess strong skills in critical thinking, self teaching, and interpersonal relationships that help companies mold me to become a leader in any environment. Has an obsession with self-improvement and will continuously strive to achieve their goals.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Javascript, React, Node JS, Express, Socket IO, Ruby, Rails, HTML5, CSS, C++, Java, Python

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Good Samaritan - Demo Github

A real-time Q/A application where travelers are able to ask any question around the world, and only nearby local users are only able to answer their question

- Used ZipcodeAPI to curate a list of local questions just from a user's zip code
- Implemented a React frontend, and a Node JS backend (Express, Socket.lo) to create a real-time messaging system

Mars Weather App - Github

A weather app where users are able to view the weather on Mars and Earth and see a comparison side-by-side

- Utilized NASA API and OpenWeatherMap API to display the weather on Mars and Earth
- Collaborated with another developer to build out the React frontend
- Built and managed data from a Rails backend to collect and show user and weather information

Curated - Github

A social media website where users are able to showcase their creative works

- Made with a Javascript frontend and Rails backend
- Managed the Rails backend database to bring crucial info to the webpage
- Built a bcrypt authentication for the backend to handle User login and signup information

EXPERIENCE

Personal Computer Business

Entrepreneur

Pearland.TX

12/2014 - Present

- Build personal computers for friends, family, and neighbors
- Identified, learned, and solved PC problems whenever they occurred
- Donated PC equipment and components to those less fortunate

The Teahouse Tapioca and Tea

Team Leader / IT Tech

Pearland, TX 12/2018 - 03/2020

Lead a team of 2-4 people to cook, prepare, and serve drinks in a fast paced working environment

- Fixed and managed technical equipment that broke down to save time and repair costs
- Quickly comprehended technical problems, in order to explain unexpected errors to superiors, in a simple and timely
- Setup equipment for big events and promotions

Fry's Electronics

Webster, TX 08/2018 - 11/2018

Sales Associate

Provide customers with assistance and knowledge of up-to-date technology

- Sold expensive computer equipment and components
- Educate customers to help them solve their own computer issues

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

Houston, TX

Houston, TX

Alvin, TX

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

03/2020 - 06/2020

University of Houston

08/2017 - Present

Ongoing education for Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Alvin Community College

08/2013 - 06/2017

Associate's Degree: General Studies